

## **Ibrahim Karam**

UNDERGRADUATE / FULLSTACK .NET DEVELOPER

6th of October, Giza, Egypt

14/10/2001

Ebrahem.karm23@gmail.com

+201121013349

@ibrahim-karam

ibrahimkaram23

#### **PROFILE**

I study at Helwan University, specializing in business information systems (BIS). I study business like accounting and management and information systems like programming, databases and operating systems, and I love programming very much, specifically programming websites. I am always looking forward to more experiences and experiences, and I have a passion because I love what I do.

I also have a YouTube channel where I summarize the study materials for my friends and also post about technology.

Click here to go to it.

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### JR. FULL-STACK .NET DEVELOPER (FULL-TIME)

Ministry of Planning and Economic Development

APR 2023 - Present

Cairo - Egypt

• My responsibility is to work on digital transformation projects for the Republic of Egypt.

#### JR. .NET DEVELOPER (PART-TIME)

Technology and Business Integration - TBI

APR 2023 - Present DEC 2022 - APR 2023 (Full-Time)

♥ EI-Sheikh Zayed - Giza

The company works to integrate business with information technology, especially electronic invoices. We create systems that integrate companies with the invoice system of the Egyptian Tax Authority.

• I am responsible for creating and maintaining websites, desktop apps, and windows services and creating APIs.

### ICT SUPPORT (FULL-TIME)

**United Nations Climate** Change Conference (COP27)

OCT 2022 - NOV 2022

Sharm-Elsheikh - Egypt

Climate Conference 27th edition held in Sharm El Sheikh -Egypt for one month.

My responsibilities are as follows:

- Audio and Visual team leader.
- The mobile application tester detects any bugs or
- Operating the network, operating laptops, connecting them to the conference domain, and giving permissions to users.
- Help united nations employees with any technical
- · Helping ministers and presidents' assistants with any technical issues.

#### C# PROGRAMMING LANGUAGE INSTRUCTOR

Techno Masr

AUG 2022 - DEC 2022

Tanta - Egypt

• My responsibility is to teach the attendees the basics of computers and the C# programming language.

#### .NET DEVELOPER TRAINEE

National Council for Women

Sep 2022 - Oct 2022

Nasr City - Egypt

• among my responsibilities was to create a web application to follow up on employees and add bonuses to them.

#### **WEB DESIGN TRAINEE**

## National Telecommunication Institute

Remote

Sep 2022 - Oct 2022

· Designing websites using HTML, CSS, Bootstrap and JavaScript.

#### LANGUAGES

Arabic

•••••

**English** 

•••••

#### PROGRAMMING SKILLS

- HTML CSS
- JavaScript Bootstrap
- C++ C#
- OOP(C# and C++)
- MVC
- .Net Framework
- · .Net Framework Core
- Windows Forms Applications
- Web forms Applications
- · Agile Methodology
- Object Oriented Analysis and Design
- SQL (MS SQL & My SQL)
- LINO
- Entity Framework
- REST API
- AJAX JS
- Design Patterns
- Reporting
- Basics of PHP

#### **VOLUNTEERING EXPERIENCE**

**Core Technical Team** 

Google Developer

Student Clubs - GDSC

May 2022 - Present

#### **Coding & Programming Instructor**

**Leaders Team** 

May 2022 - Oct 2022

Web Developer

Microsoft Student Partners

Dec 2021 - Oct 2022

**Business Development Specialist** 

**Our Vision CU** 

May 2021 - Sep 2021 · 5 mos

Social Media Specialist

**Leaders Team** 

Oct 2019 - Sep 2020 · 1 yr

#### **FULL STACK .NET DEVELOPER TRAINEE**

Elaraby Group

AUG 2022

Remote

- Training in creating and designing websites, databases, and backend programming.
- Using (HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, MS SQL,
- Training on creating websites using MVC technology.
- Practice creating databases.

#### MANAGER ASSISTANT (PART-TIME)

## Al-Gmmal Group

May 2020- Jul 2022

• Haram - Giza

- Follow up on the reception page of Alaraby company's requests.
- Organization of files.
- · Close accounts and budget.
- Monitor the status of electronic devices.

#### .NET DEVELOPER TRAINEE

## **Linked Gates Company**

Dec 2021 - Jan 2022

Nasr City - Egypt

- Training in creating and designing websites, databases, and backend programming.
- Training on creating websites using MVC technology.
- Practice creating databases.

#### .NET DEVELOPER TRAINEE

## National Council for Women

Sep 2021 - Oct 2021

Nasr City - Egypt

 Working on creating a government website to help individuals collect data from Participants, and we created a web application using ASP.NET technology with SQL as a database.

#### CODING AND PROGRAMMING TRAINEE

## Samsung Innovation Campus

Jul 2021 - Sep 2021

• Remote

Samsung International provided the scholarship, and I learned the following:

- Scratch programming language (Web desktop kit).
- Python programming language.
- Rurble programming language.
- C programming language.
- · Data Structures and Algorithms.
- Arduino

#### **BANKING INTERNSHIPS**

## Commercial International Bank (CIB)

I trained for two years in a row at the bank, in 2021 they trained us on financial inclusion, and in 2022 they trained us on entrepreneurship.

## **EDUCATION HISTORY**

## **Business Information Systems - BIS**

## Helwan University

Sep 2019 - Present

Expected Graduate: Jul 2023CGPA: 3.20 (Very Good)

## COURSES AND CERTIFICATES

## **Developing SQL Databases**

#### From: HackerRank

- Issued: March 2022
- Credential ID: dbf1b2d76894
- Credential URL:

Click Here to Show Certificate

## **Developing SQL Databases**

## From: Sololearn

- Issued: Jan 2022
- Credential ID: 19330917-1060
- Credential URL:

Click Here to Show Certificate

### C++ Development

#### From: Sololearn

- Issued: May 2021
- Credential ID: 19330917-1051
- Credential URL:

Click Here to Show Certificate

## Computer Network Fundamentals

# From: Information Technology Institute (ITI)

- Issued: Jul 2020
- Credential ID: VVQIDoILOB
- Credential URL:

Click Here to Show Certificate

## Programming in HTML5 with JavaScript and CSS3

## From: Information

## **Technology Institute (ITI)**

- Issued: Jul 2020
- Credential ID: pEkaOyLSJd
- Credential URI:

Click Here to Show Certificate

## Technical Support Fundamentals

## From: Google

- Issued: Aug 2021
- Credential ID: Z53Z69KQ6CWM
- Credential URL:

#### Click Here to Show Certificate

### **PROJECTS**

## **UNO ERP System**

An administrative system through which customers can create invoices and send them directly to the Egyptian Tax Authority.

It also has control over all invoices sent and printing invoices again or canceling them from the tax system.

The system also includes a mini-system for managing employees, which is UNO HR System.

• Technologies: MS SQL Server, C#, ASP.NET, AJAX, HTML, CSS, JS

## IBMS - Management System

Small ERP that manage maintenance centers, at this system I make small financial cycle and employees management system.

 Technologies: MS SQL Server, C#, ASP.NET, AJAX, HTML, CSS, JS

## **POS Desktop Application**

The POS make sales transactions and make invoices and Receipts then send it to ETA.

• Technologies: MS SQL Server, C#, ASP.NET.

# Beymen - Online Registration System for AUC Lebanon branch

Online events management system.

• Technologies: MS SQL Server, C#, ASP.NET, AJAX, HTML, CSS, JS